

# **ABOUT ME**

My name is Matthew Callahan and I am a software engineer in Phoenix, Arizona. I have over ten years of experience in web and desktop software development using Scrum, Kanban, and XP agile methodologies. Learning the dynamic landscape of computer programming is my passion.

## **CONTACT**

Email: matthew.callahan@outlook.com

Phone: 630-988-1555

Homepage: mfcallahan.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mfcallahan1

GitHub: github.com/mfcallahan

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft Technology Associate: Developer

#### **KEY SKILLS**

#### Languages

C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python

#### **Frameworks**

.NET 4.8 & .NET Core 3.1: Web API, Entity Framework, SignalR

Angular 10:

Material, RxJs, NgRx

ArcGIS:

JavaScript API, .NET SDK, Server

#### **Testing**

NUint, Jasmine, Selenium, Cypress

#### **Dev Tools**

Git, Azure, Jenkins, Splunk

# MATTHEW CALLAHAN

#### **EDUCATION**



# **University of Wisconsin-Madison**

Bachelor of Science, Geographic Information Systems

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Staff Engineer | Republic Services, Scottsdale, AZ | May 2019 - Present

- Lead a team of eight developers and testers, overseeing talent development, skill set improvement, and acting as a mentor to all team members.
- Established and implemented a standard application architecture for greenfield development (.NET & .NET Core back end/Angular front end).
- Implemented unit test standards for the team and led effort to increase test coverage on all apps, reducing the number of production bugs.
- Authored coding conventions and style guide documents for developers and currently leading effort to refactor all applications to follow these guidelines.
- Technologies used: .NET, .NET Core, C#, Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, SQL Server, ArcGIS.

# Sr. Developer | Republic Services, Scottsdale, AZ | Dec 2018 - May 2019

- Developed enterprise GIS web applications which provided data mapping and route visualization tools to assist in business operations (ASP.NET, Angular).
- Developed APIs and services to deliver spatial data to teams and applications throughout the company (ASP.NET Web API).
- Supported desktop application development for GIS data analysis and batch data processing (ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, Python).
- Implemented a uniform Git branching strategy and code review process for all application repositories.

## Software Engineer | Carvana, Tempe, AZ | Feb 2018 - Dec 2018

- Primary job function was back end development to create and maintain the APIs and microservices which powered carvana.com (C#, .NET & .NET Core).
- Supported front end development to maintain and enhance a mobile responsive UI for a vehicle inventory search engine (JS ES6+, React/Redux, AngularJS).
- Implemented A/B testing to help drive data analytics and deliver the best UX.

## Application Developer | CBRE, Phoenix, AZ | Jan 2011 - Feb 2018

- Developed web applications which provided mapping and site selection data analysis tools for real estate brokers and their clients (ASP.NET MVC).
- Developed desktop applications for GIS data processing and analysis (C# .NET, WinForms, MapBasic, ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, Python).
- Administered on-prem servers (Windows Server, IIS, SQL Server, ArcGIS Server).
- Employee of the year "MVP" award, 2012.

## GIS Technician | CBRE, Phoenix, AZ | Mar 2008 - Jan 2011

- Developed scripts and desktop GIS tools to automate tasks and improve workflow efficiency of GIS Technicians.
- Created custom maps, demographic reports, and market research reports for commercial real estate brokers, affording them the ability to make well informed decisions and best serve their clients.
- Employee of the Quarter, 1st guarter 2009.

Resume ver: 2020.07.2